So, good day, fun day.
So, always funny is these, you know, the
fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh in the
free agency.
Um really where a lot of our scouts work
comes into play.
Um
you know,
Farmer was a
He was a guy we kind of had targeted
even earlier. It reminds me a little
Bernie.
You know, when we took Bernie, remember
in the third that year?
Um we think very highly of Farmer. He's
a big, powerful man.
Um that he's going to be a really good
addition to the to our O-line, not only
from a
talent standpoint, but also from a
cultural standpoint. He fits what we
look for.
Um and we also think he's got some swing
at at tackle. So, it'd be nice to
add him in the mix and uh watch him
compete. Um we took Bryce, you know,
from Oregon in the
another linebacker, athletic, fast.
Um
a blue card guy for us.
A really special
like dude. I mean, here's a guy, you
know, he He was drafted by the Astros.
Um
and he was walking on, earning it, and
has been just a tremendous player for
University of Oregon.
Um Gums was a is an interesting guy cuz
he was a walk-on at Northern Illinois,
played wideout, tight end.
Goes to Florida, they move him to
defensive end. We think this kid's got
some upside. He's a He's a tremendous
athlete. Thinking he'll help us on
teams. Think we can develop him, you
know, kind of as an outside backer
rusher.
Um we came back and took Curry who's
local. Actually watched I actually
watched Caden play in the state
championship game against Westfield.
Um and he was pretty dominant there.
And, you know, to watch, you know, him
go to Ohio State, play his whole career,
and wait till his fourth year, then get
his chance, and and have a big, you
know, have a really big senior season.
Um but he's a really good He's a really
good, hard-playing football player,
local guy. Um but excited to get him.
Uh Seth is a guy we
you know, we've been watching here for a
while. You know, he was at
you know, he had the incident when he
was at Oklahoma, which we know and we
vetted hard. You know, his relationship
with our running back coach, our
relationship with coaches at Kentucky
and at New Mexico State. Um I've known
the head coach at New Mexico State for a
lot of years, and you know, they all
they all speak very highly of the young
man and who he is and and how he works.
But, he adds a real physical element at
running back. And then, then one we
didn't think was going to be there, and
Burks, who's extremely talented. Why he
was there, I don't know. Um fortunate
for us.
He's fast, he's explosive. Um we think
he's got a real chance to help us. And
we And we'll We'll try to get him worked
in the return game, too, even though he
hadn't done a lot of it. Um we think
he's got upside as a returner.
All right.
That's the group. Fire away.
Chris, did just get it out of the way.
Did just nothing apparently come up with
Kenny and AR free agency Nothing.
Nothing yet. No, nothing yet.
>> Surprising that there
some interest.
>> Nothing surprises me anymore. And I I
just think it's
we have a little patience here and and
see what happens, you know? I mean, I
think I talked to a lot of y'all about,
you know, a long time at the owners
meetings about it. And
Um so, we just kind of we'll let it play
out as it does over time. Do you expect
them to be here next week or not? I
don't know. I don't know. I don't have
an answer to that.
It's voluntary right now, so. You
position-wise were
There's not not a
uh criticism, but kind of predictable
maybe in this draft. Like you hit the
needs. Um
Did the Did the need and the the board
measure up like uniquely in a unique way
this year? It's like I mean, I think I
we've kind of talked about it all that.
Like we wanted to get younger on
defense. That was a
and faster. Like we needed to add some
more speed, and we think we've been able
to do that. And it kind of It was a
like it was a You saw in the first Now,
the one thing if you noticed in the
third round, like offensive players were
just kind of flying off the board. Um
and so, there was a little more depth on
the defensive side throughout the draft.
We kind of felt that the whole time.
With With Farmer, do you expect him to
be somebody that can come in and and
contribute right away, or is it more
like dude working along cuz
I mean, he hasn't experience starting,
but also you have a starting group
already. He's talented. Here I mean,
look, you can't
with competition makes everybody better.
It just does. All right. So, he he will
definitely be talented enough. How fast
he gets it and if he earns it, then
he'll play.
I'm saying on the same Along the same
lines, do you think your line
is your line isn't settled, or do you
think like do you want to see it play
out? Yeah, I mean, I feel really good
about where we're at right now as an
offensive line. Hey, Aaron. Yeah, one
mic. Yeah, no, I feel good about the
offensive line right now, but adding
Farmer to the fold, uh I think is a huge
get. Uh he's physical. Um he did some
really good things in Kentucky. So, he's
going to come in uh and learn the
offense and learn the system, and we'll
go from there. Chris, Farmer is is the
plan for mostly swing tackle, or do you
think he'll compete for any spots
inside? Um we'll probably start him
inside, you know, here during OTAs and
during the summer camp. And then when we
get to training camp, we'll mix and
match like we do.
Seems like this class, maybe even more
than others, multi-year starters, heavy
SEC, heavy big 12. Like Yeah. the top of
college football. Do you
emphasize that, or do you feel that? It
Yes. Yes, without question. I mean, we
And we vetted that I mean, we we talked
a long time about that, you know,
getting guys that have
that have history, you know, have play
history, and really had high
competitive stamina. Okay? So, when you
go and play at these schools in the SEC,
um like each week, I mean, it's
Look, it's not the NFL, but it's
probably the closest thing you can get.
It's very competitive. So, you know,
when you when you're talking about a guy
like CJ,
um
and, you know, Halsey who moved up along
the way, um what they did was
impressive. So, I mean, and throughout
the class, like that was a That was an
emphasis. That's a good catch by you,
cuz it was.
Chris, with you said you really vetted
Magallen. Yep.
Do you just make the decision that
he messed up and and
he'd learn from it? I mean, how how When
When you vetted, what does that Yeah, I
mean,
like I
Look, I'm a second-chance guy. I mean, I
I just
like, you know, how long do you keep
punishing him for it? Um you know, to
his credit, he's gone and and like if
you hear the real Like, I don't know if
he really wanted to leave New Mexico
State,
but I think just financially it was so
he didn't have a choice. I mean, that's
kind of what Tony had said to me. He
said, "Look, Chris, I He needed to go
just cuz financially it was the best
thing for him." So,
you know, he's had a good track record.
Feel good about who he is as a
you know, you learn your lesson, you
make a mistake, you
pay the price for it, and then you move
on.
Chris, I know you mentioned last night
you feel like
CJ Allen is probably your Mike
linebacker, or at least would trend that
way coming into the summer. What What's
your vision for what Bryce can be in
that linebacker room? Yeah, we I mean,
we think he can play both. Okay? So, we
think he can play Mike and Will. He'll
be part of the competition, you know,
with the rest of the group we got there.
Did you say something about Gums um
edge hand outside linebacker or
something to start? Like in loose deep
You know, they stand up all the time.
So, we're going to drop him and do some
things with him. But, when I say I He's
an edge player.
>> Okay. That's what he is. Chris, it looks
like with a lot of these later picks, I
mean,
special teams, special teams, special
teams. It It really looks like what a
lot of these guys may cut their teeth
on. You can't make it. Like it it And
like even these
the higher I mean, even the high picks,
like
it's hard to get to Sunday and 48-man
dressing 48 men if you don't have enough
people to play on teams. And we were
excellent last year on special teams,
and we want to continue to do that. Um
so, yeah, I mean, a young player's first
avenue to get to the field is he's got
to be able to do something on teams. So,
that that was That was a definite
emphasis, too. Talk about getting
younger and faster on defense. Did the
defense also get more versatile through
this draft? Um I think so. We'll see how
it plays out.
Um
you know, cuz we've had We have a
You know, I like our depth at safety a
lot. And, you know, we'll see how it
ends up playing out. But, guys we have
guys that can play interchangeable
parts. So, yeah. Chris, I'm curious. You
mentioned uh Caden Curry, a familiar
face around these parts, obviously. But,
how closely did you kind of keep up with
him? Um and what stood out to you about
bringing him to here to the Colts?
Because I watched him play in the state
Believe it or not, there was another kid
on the other side. It was Austin Booker.
Um you know, they had two ends. Um and I
just remember Caden like they put him on
offense, and we couldn't tackle him. I
mean, he was like they'd have 10 guys,
and he'd be dragging. He was a big,
strong kid in high school. So, what And
then I knew Ryan Day and them. I I can't
remember that year. We I was talking to
Ryan Day, and he was in town actually
recruiting him, trying to
finalize everything.
Um so, I've kind of followed him through
his career. And really, his first 3
years, he was a
role player and like really good on
teams. Like really good. And then, like
Ohio State,
like Caden had to I mean, they're
recruiting guys behind him. Like it's
not like the cupboard's bare at Ohio
State. They're bringing other ends in.
And he This kid Larry Johnson texted me
today. He said, "He's one of the better
football players I've been around." And
he is. I mean, he had 11 sacks in a week
10.
Why do you think he is just arm length
wide though? I thought I mean, you bring
up his production. I mean, that's no
joke in that department.
>> Yeah, no. I mean, sometimes the
physical, you know, measurements, you
know, people will knock you down, but
we'll see how he does. I think he'll do
well. I do. Sam, what stands out to you
about Burks and what he can do at the
receiver position in this role? Well, I
think the first thing's speed. I mean,
he's a 4-2 speed guy that can fly. When
you put the ball in his hands, he can
make plays with it, and that's what you
want. You want to create explosive
plays, get the guy, you know, get the
ball in this guy's hand any way you can.
And like Chris said earlier, just in in
the return game, if he comes in the
return game, too, that'll be very
beneficial for us. Shane, what do you
What do you like about dropping CJ Allen
into the the culture of this team? Yeah,
I mean, everything I've heard about him
through the vetting process, just the
toughness, the edge he plays with, the
leadership,
it's impressive. And I can't wait to get
him in the building. I think he's going
to be a great leader for this football
team,
not only next year, but in the future as
well. Shane, you mentioned earlier in
the week the things the traits you look
for in receivers. Does Does Deion kind
of check off a lot of those boxes with
his separation and release and all that?
>> Yeah, absolutely. I think that's I mean,
when you watch him verse press, even for
being a shorter guy, I mean, he can get
off press coverage.
He's got a good quick first step, good
release, good burst, and then the
separation at the top routes is is
really good as well. Shane, with the two
edge guys you guys added to the mix with
Curry and Gums, how do you view them
helping just kind of round out this
group? I don't know if there's maybe
like a defined starter out of the set of
Latou yet, but how do you view this
group as a whole kind of coming
together? Yeah, I think it's a solid
group, and I think we got a lot of depth
there at that position right now. So,
like I said, those guys are going to
come in and compete
you know, with the other guys. Obviously
being young players, but they're going
to come in and learn
and grow in the system. We'll go from
there.
Shane, how do you see Hem's role maybe
as kind of being
just eaten up by multiple guys? How How
do you kind of Yeah, we'll see how that
plays out. I mean, we got a lot of lot
lot of time to go right now. But like I
hit it with you guys the other day, I
mean, Duwuane's a guy,
you know, Westbrook that we signed is a
guy, and Treadwell's a guy that's been
here. So,
we'll go through OTAs, we'll go through
training camp, and then obviously we got
Burks as well. So, we'll see.
For for one or both of you, either
quarterback, is that is that something
that was a conversation for you today at
all
at some point? Not I mean, we looked at
a few, but not really. Yeah.
Is that me? I'm sorry.
That is a That is a fine.
>> [laughter]
>> Going forward with obviously you have
seven rounds done, but now you have
undrafted free agents. What goes into
picking who to sign from here on out out
of the rookies that went undrafted? So,
our scouts, like during the starts about
the fifth round, we'll start kind of
lining guys up and calling, "Okay,
here's our targets. Here's where" And
then, of course, if there's somebody
left on the board.
Um but we prioritize, we start kind of
recruiting, seeing what, you know, who's
going to be available. Then once the
draft ends, it's a frenzy. You know, now
you're recruiting and trying to get the
guys in the boat.
And the one thing we've seen over the
last I mean, I think you see it every
year, but
um this
this try
>> [laughter]
>> I'm sorry. This try I don't know what
I'm trying to say. Uh the tryout
camp we have, like we'll find two or
three guys in that camp every year um
that can help us. So,
>> [laughter]
>> Where's Hey, where is Mike Wells when
you need him?
Where is Mike Wells when you need Mike
Wells?
>> [laughter]
>> I swore I turned the dadgum sound off
earlier.
Chris, uh for real though, it does look
like you guys were kind of deliberate
leaning into like leadership qualities
with a lot of these guys. Was that
something intentional for you?
Hey, we look, we always keep a like it's
always at the first and foremost like
when we're talking about players. Um
sometimes it works, sometimes it it just
happened to work today. We got some guys
that we really
have some real strong qualities as
leaders. Now, they got to come in and
earn their way, and and but we think
over time it it'll show.
Let's do a couple more. Allen had the
knee late in the year, but then ran a
few weeks ago. Is he good to go? Yeah,
he's good. His workout was good, so
yeah, we feel good about it.
Chris, I know you told us
earlier last week on on Kenny and
Anthony you said at the time you you
viewed those as kind of separate things.
Kenny saying Kenny, you know, you might
give some some leeway to and still feel
like Anthony could potentially have a
future here. Is that It's
It's the same as it was. Yeah, nothing's
really changed in that way.
Um just Shane,
this is just random, but with Halsey,
the energy that he gave us on the Zoom
call was
on a thousand. So, I'm just curious,
either one of you can answer, but like
what was it like on your end hearing
from him because he was so excited? It
was hard to hear him. They were going
nuts on that phone call. I mean, there
was probably so many people in the
background, but it's exciting anytime
you make those calls and you hear it
what's going on in the background and
the families are excited.
But he's got a lot of juice and a lot of
energy, and he's a damn good football
player, so we're excited to have him.
Hey Chris, one thing about the Cats in
the box is
how many first round grades did you have
this year? Just curious. I mean, never
mind I said
Is that really? Yeah, we had 14.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Yeah, I mean,
um
I don't know. We other years we've
I'd have to look at it, but no, I mean,
any it usually varies between 14 to
depending 20 It just 25 to 14 usually.
Depend I think 18 we had
That was a loaded I mean, that draft was
really good. But it's all it fluctuates.
You don't know. And then like what's a
first round grade? Because sometimes you
take a guy in the sec I mean, like
Darius and Braden Smith probably looking
back on it probably should have been
first round picks. I mean, and that
happens.